(停车场)
(工厂前方  行尸  天使)
你来这里是...
Are you here --
我来这里是找你帮忙的
I'm here because I need your help.
《行尸走肉》
抱歉占用了你的拖车
Sorry for taking over your trailer.
我长大时身边有很多人
I grew up ‭with a lot of people around.
我习惯了
I'm used to it.
大家庭吗
Big family?
是教养院
Uh...group home.
但这跟那不一样
This isn't like that, though.
至少没那么糟糕
Not the bad parts, at least.
有史以来头一回  我有了归属感
For the first time, I feel like I belong.
努力确保你和萨沙融入
Trying to make sure you and Sasha became a part of this
让我也融入了
made me a part of this.
我刚来时
When I was first here...
心不在这里
I was never here.
我
I, um...
我总觉得接近别人很难
I always found it hard getting close to anyone --
邻居  朋友
neighbors, friends...
男友
boyfriends.
你有空该谈谈恋爱
You should try it sometime.
就算不会持续
Even if it doesn't last.
我要跟铁匠聊聊多做几根长矛的事
I'm gonna talk to our blacksmith about making more spears.
也许我们能和神之国交换防弹衣
Maybe we can trade with the Kingdom for some body armor.
问题是  我们真正需要的是防暴装备
Thing is, what we really need is riot gear.
我
I was...
那天在找书看
looking for something to read the other day.
子弹你可以留着
You can have the bullets.
我不知道你有枪
I didn't know you had a gun.
我之前没有
I didn't.
现在有了
I do now.
萨沙  别走  现在别走
Sasha, don't go -- not yet.
罗西塔不是来这里训练人们的
Rosita didn't come here to train people.
你们都要去杀尼根
You're both going after Negan.
但没有别人的帮助  你们做不到
But you can't do that without people.
许多人
A lot of people.
我们谈过了
We've talked about this.
我知道你的想法
I know what you think.
我很感激
And I appreciate that.
但我不会改变主意
But I'm not gonna change my mind.
她也不会
She's not.
玛姬知道罗西塔来了吗
Does Maggie know Rosita's here yet?
我想不知道
Uh, I-I-I don't think so.
我没有...
I didn't...
你该告诉她
You should tell her.
告诉她一切
About all of it.
现在还不行
No. Not yet.
她
Sh--
我还在准备
I'm still -- I'm still getting ready.
问题是  罗西塔要去
And the thing is, Rosita is going,
不管有没有我
with or without me.
所以应该有我
So it should be with me.
-那我也去  -我也是
- Then I'll go, too. - Me, too.
不行
No.
山顶寨必须为之后发生的事做好准备
The Hilltop has to be ready for what happens after.
玛姬需要你们
Maggie needs you.
她也需要你
She needs you, too.
不再需要了
Not anymore.
她有了你们大家
She has everyone else,
大家有了她
and they have her.
你可以留下
You can stay.
我知道的
I know you can.
但我知道你不会  她也不会
But I know you won't and she won't,
但我希望你留下
but I wish you would.
因为你本可能长寿  如果去了就不是了
'Cause it's a long life, and then it isn't.
你需要什么都可以拿走
You can take anything else you need.
但你和罗西塔得和玛姬谈谈
But you and Rosita need to talk to Maggie.
这是你欠她的
You owe her that much.
听着
Listen...
伊妮德
Enid...
玛姬信任你
Maggie trusts you.
你得保护她  无论发生什么
You have to protect her, no matter what.
她是这里的未来
She's the future of this place.
我知道
I know it.
你也是
So are you.
帮我保管
Hold on to this for me.
这是给孩子的
It's for the baby.
也许我走后你能继续编
Maybe you can work on it while I'm gone.
好
Okay.
萨沙
Sasha...
嗯
Yeah.
十分钟后
In 10 minutes,
我会告诉玛姬发生了什么
I'm gonna tell Maggie what's going on.
在此期间  你想怎么做是你的事
It's up to you what you want to do with that.
我照你的吩咐做了
I'm doing what you asked.
救世军来了
The Saviors are coming!
我们得去找玛姬
We have to get Maggie.
- 她在哪  - 快来
- Where is she? ‭  - Come on!
我们躲在哪
Where do we hide?
我们不躲
We're not hiding.
好  进来
All right, get in.
这通往另一头
It goes to the other side.
我们得赶在玛姬之前出来
We got to get out before Maggie does.
我们来不及的
We'll never make it in time.
快
Come on!
待在下面
Just stay down there.
我来引开他们
I'll keep them away.
这不是去亚历山大的那批人
They aren't the same ones who came to Alexandria.
西蒙  你好啊
Simon! Hello.
你也好啊  格雷戈里
Right back at you, Gregory.
你好
Hello.
我们没料到你这么快就回来了
We weren't, uh, expecting you back so soon.
想去我办公室谈吗
You want to talk in my office?
我的人找到了一瓶琴酒
I got a bottle of gin my people found.
你喜欢喝琴酒  对吧
You're a gin man, right?
我的
Oh, I'm a man of...
口味经常变化
shifting specifics of tastes in transition.
我现在喜欢龙舌兰了
I'm into tequila now.
陈酿  金黄色
Añejo. Reposado.
啜饮  混合
Sipping, mixing...
口味的世界
Un mundo de sabor.
琴酒像是松节油
Gin seems like turpentine.
那晚喝了琴蕾鸡尾酒  口味就变了
It happened quick with a gimlet the other night.
我是个非同寻常的人
I'm an unusual kind of creature.
知道吗
You know what?
我尊重这点
I respect that.
嗯  龙舌兰
Yeah. Tequila.
心理笔记  记住了
Mental note. Locked.
很好
Great.
没必要闲聊了
Oh, no need to talk.
这是一次短暂的拜访
This is hopefully a quick visit.
我能为你做什么
Well, what can I do for you?
这问题问得好
That's an excellent question.
但是啊  答案可就没那么好了
Alas, the answer's not so excellent.
你这里的某个人...
You have a certain somebody that, uh...
现在要变成尼根的人
now needs to be Negan's certain somebody,
所以你能为我做的就是指明他所在的方向
so what you can do for me is point me in their direction.
你指的是谁
So, who is it?
你准备好带路
You get your pointy finger up,
我会告诉你的
and I'll tells ya.
达里尔
Daryl.
那个隧道是你挖的吗
Did you dig that tunnel?
玛姬认为我们得有个出去的捷径
Maggie thought we needed a quick way out.
所以我就挖了一条
So I made one.
我们出来了  现在怎么办
Well, we're out. So now what?
你知道的
You know.
假如这辆能点着  我会抽走一些油
If this one starts, I'll siphon some gas.
我只要找到...
I just got to find --
那里有个空水瓶
There's an empty water bottle.
我以为这辆能点着  但是...
I thought this was the one, but...
喜欢吗
Like it?
我做的
I made it.
这车点不着
Car's dead.
你在哪儿学的拆弹
Where'd you learn to disarm bombs?
你之前是军队的吗
Were you in the Army?
我认识的一个人教我的
Someone I knew.
不是他
Not him.
听着  我不是来玩"相互了解"的
Listen, I'm not here to play "Get to Know You,"
所以我们要么谈任务  要么不说话
so either we talk about the mission or we don't.
好吧
Okay.
耶稣说有几栋建筑
Jesus said there's some buildings,
二三四层楼高
two, three, four stories,
就在救世堂外面的东边
just outside the sanctuary to the east of it.
那些建筑中至少有一栋能看到他们的后院
At least one of them should have a line of sight to the rear courtyard,
就在行尸围栏后面
past the fence with the walkers on it.
我们躲起来  等着  然后从那里狙击
We hole up, we wait, we take a shot from there.
如果我们不得不靠近
If we have to get closer,
外围有一些薄弱点
there's some weak spots in the perimeter
也许我们可以利用
we might still be able to take advantage of,
但假如可以的话
but if we can,
我还是建议我们待在外面  做得干净些
I say we stay outside, do it clean.
也许还能活着回来
Maybe make it out of there alive.
你有意见吗
You see a problem with that?
我想确保我们杀了他
I want to make sure we get him.
那就意味着我们得进去
That means we go in.
假如我们在远处射偏了
If we shoot from a distance and miss,
就没有第二次机会了
we don't get another chance.
我不会射偏的
I won't miss.
就算你射伤了他  他也死不了
Even if you shoot and graze him, he doesn't die.
我不会射偏的
I won't miss.
假如我们进去被抓住了...
If we go in and get caught --
我不会被抓住的
I won't get caught.
你到底有什么毛病
What the hell's wrong with you?
被抓住就没第二次机会了
They take us, we don't get another try.
因为他们会杀了我们
Because they'll kill us.
如果我们待在外面  还能活命
If we're out here, we're alive.
还有第二次机会
We get another go.
我没什么毛病  萨沙
Nothing is wrong with me, Sasha.
我要确保杀死他
I'm gonna make sure he's dead.
假如这对你而言太过了
Look, if this is too much for you,
你想要退出  现在就可以走
you want to bail, now's your chance.
我哪里也不去
I'm not going anywhere.
-我已经受够谈论这个了  -很好
- Well, I'm done talking about it. - Good.
也许你会考虑一下
Maybe you'll think about it.
也许你会重新想想
Maybe you'll change your mind
该以什么代价达成目标
about what it takes to get what you want.
-我这有鲜菜  -停
- I've got fresh veggies. - Stop.
它们是蔬菜
They're vegetables.
用全称
Use the whole word.
我们有的是时间
We have time.
好吧
Okay.
我有蔬菜  他们让我拿过来
I have these vegetables they told me to bring over,
而且  篮子很重
and the basket's pretty heavy.
对我来说很重
For me, I mean.
对你可能不重  拿着
Probably not you. Uh, here.
装到卡车上去
Load them in the truck,
如果你来菜园那边找我
and, uh, if you meet me by the garden,
-我可以把剩下的...  -停
- I can get you the rest... - ‭Stop.
我不知道你以为我或我们是什么人
I don't know who you think I am or who we are.
自己装车  我很忙
Load them yourself. I'm busy.
-抱歉  很抱歉  -姑娘
- Sorry. I'm sorry. - Girl,
赶紧捡起来  然后滚开
pick that shit up right now and scram.
这个我收了
And I'll take that.
快点
Now.
别逼我弄死你  姑娘
Don't make me cut it off you, girl.
哈兰·卡森医生吗
Dr. Harlan Carson, correct?
你需要检查吗
Do you need a checkup?
也许吧  好几年没查过了
Probably. It's been a few years,
但我不是为这个来的
but I'm not here for that.
上次你们来的时候  我们已经把
We already gave you as much medicine as we could spare
-能交的药都交出来了  -没错
- the last time you were here. - ‭Yes, you did.
但我们不是来要药的
But we're not here to take more of that.
祝贺你
Congratulations!
你升职了
You're moving up in the world.
尼根要你住过去
Negan wants you where he is.
你是个重要人物  哈兰
You're an important fellow, Harlan.
跟我们走
You're coming with us.
听着  这里有病人需要我
Look, I -- I have patients here that need me.
尼根为什么要两个医生
Why does Negan need two doctors?
我想我的表情已经传达了信息
Well, I think my look may have conveyed the information.
大家都说我的脸很传神
People say I have an expressive face.
但如果不够传神  我来重复你的问题
But if not, let me repeat your question.
我们为什么要两个医生
Why do we need two doctors?
回答是  不需要两个
Answer, we don't.
所以
So...
我哥哥惹恼了什么人  所以被杀了吗
my brother pissed someone off, get himself killed?
差不多吧
Something like that.
非常残忍可怖
Very, very ugly stuff.
节哀顺变
My condolences.
但是  该走了
But it's time.
我的病历都是整理好的
All of my charts are in order.
你得对这里的医疗方案做一些安排
You need to make arrangements for some kind of medical care here,
特别是我的长期病患
especially for my ongoing patients.
我会的
I will.
-我得收拾行李  -不用了
- I need to pack. - You don't.
你要的东西我们都有
We have everything you need,
没有的我们也会弄来
and what we don't, we'll get.
你喜欢冰淇淋吗
Hey, you like ice cream?
我们有冰淇淋
We have ice cream.
我们有位女士会做小豆蔻冰淇淋
We have a lady ‭that makes cardamom gelato.
不骗你
Shit you not.
差点忘了  把那个放下
Oh! Almost forgot. Set that down.
要公平合理
Well, fair is fair.
涉及到医疗方案
We're not leaving you high and dry
我们可不会让你们孤立无援
when it comes to medical solutions.
去看看吧
Go on.
(阿司匹林)
西蒙  能和你谈谈吗
Simon, a word?
听着
Look,
我觉得我已经证明了我能和尼根合作
I think I've proven that I can work with Negan.
我能做到
I'm a can-do guy,
但我需要我的人信任我
but I got to hang on to my peoples' trust.
不然  你不知道谁会取代我
Otherwise, you don't know who might take over.
其他人可能不怎么想合作
You know, someone else might not be so cooperative.
他们可能有很疯狂的想法
They might have crazy ideas.
谁会取代你
Who might take over?
-什么疯狂的想法  -我不知道
- What crazy ideas? - I don't know.
我只是在考虑最坏的情况
I'm just considering worst-case scenarios.
我想说的是
You know, What I'm saying is,
我了解人性  不难揣测
I know human nature, and it isn't inconceivable.
我明白你的担忧
I hear your concern.
我也不是不知道  对吧
I'm not insensitive to it, ‭right?
如果你担心那种问题...
If you're having problems of that nature...
那就来找我
come to see me.
随时都可以
Anytime.
我不知道去哪里找你
I don't know where to go.
我会安排的...
I'll arrange it so that...
你只要告诉守卫你是谁...
...you just tell the guard who you are...
他就会放你进来
...and he'll let you right in.
只要你别耍什么花招
Long as ‭there's no shenanigans afoot.
没有花招
There will be none.
-我只是想让你考虑一下  -很好
- I just -- I just would like you to consider -- - Wonderful.
我们会开几瓶龙舌兰
We'll crack open some tequila.
我们会聊聊
We'll talk.
我们会解决的
We'll work it out.
你是一名优秀的生产者
You're a good producer for us.
-我不想你压力太大  -好吧
- I don't want you to be so stressed. - Yeah.
如果你能放了我的医生  我压力会小很多
I'd be a lot less stressed if you'd leave my doctor.
格雷戈里
Gregory...
明白了  没问题
Got it. Okay.
我不会再要求了
I won't ask again.
你打算杀了那人
‭You were gonna kill that guy.
他会发现我们
He was gonna find us.
他不会  他也没找到
He wasn't, and he didn't.
他该死
He deserved to die.
你来到这里以后
Ever since you got here,
你还没和我说过一句话
you haven't said a word to me.
你能看着我吗
Would you look at me?
求你了
Please?
达里尔
Daryl...
对不起
I'm sorry.
那不是你的错
It wasn't your fault.
是我的错
It was.
不
No.
不是的
It wasn't.
你是这世上仅存的善与美好
You're one of the good things in this world.
格伦一直是这么想的
That's what Glenn thought.
他肯定不会错
And he would know,
因为他也是这世上仅存的善与美好
'cause he was ‭one of the good things, too.
而且...
And, uh...
我也想杀了那人
I wanted to kill that guy, too.
我想把他们都绑起来  看着他们死去
I wanted to string them all up and watch them die.
但我们必须要赢
But we have to win.
帮我赢
Help me win.
没问题的
This'll work.
现在
Now.
上车
‭Get in!
有情况吗
‭Anything?
尼根还是没出来
Negan still hasn't come out.
不过尤金在外面
But Eugene's out there.
尤金
Eugene?
看起来
It looks like...
他似乎在指挥别人
he's ordering people around.
有他自己的打算吧
Playing some angle.
能教教我怎么系这种绳结吗
Will you teach me those knots?
我知道很多种  但没见过这种
I know a bunch, but not those.
很快  这些都不重要了
Won't matter soon.
或许重要呢
It might.
好吧  我教你
Yeah, I'll show you.
首先是第一个
All right, here's the first one.
像这样在你手里交叉
Cross it over your hand like that.
然后把上面这一圈拉下来  折上去
Then you take the top loop, bring it down, up,
从后面穿过来  然后这样
and back through, then...
会了吗
Got it?
我试试
Let me try.
你知道吗
You know...
我们很幸运有你跟我们在一起
we got lucky, having you with us.
你什么都知道
You know how to do everything.
约翰尼
Johnny.
我关于炸弹的知识都是他教的
That's who taught me about bombs.
是个生存主义者  "有备族"什么的
Survivalist, prepper-type shit.
关于车的知识是马库斯教的
Marcus taught me about cars.
他是个技工
He was a mechanic...
一心想做个特技车手
and a wannabe stunt driver.
混球一个
And an asshole.
绳结是猎人教的
Knot-tying was from Chaser.
当然  他真名不叫这个
Yeah, that wasn't his real name.
还有其他一些人
There were others.
是你去华盛顿的路上失去的那些伙伴吗
Were those people you lost on the way to D.C.?
不  不是他们
No, not them.
有很多人想要保护我
A lot of guys wanted to protect me,
就好像我自己完全保护不了自己一样
like there was no way i could know how to take care of myself.
我当时确实保护不了
And I didn't.
我讨厌那种感觉
And I hated the way that felt.
所以我顺着他们来
So I rolled with it.
他们甚至都没有注意到
They didn't even notice I was picking up
我把他们的东西都学会了  还比他们做得更好
everything they knew how to do and doing it better.
我比他们强了就离开了
Then I'd outgrow them and bounce.
做爱只是觉得好玩
The sex was just for fun.
世界都玩完了
When the world's over,
大家都该随心所欲些
everyone should be getting their rocks off.
你跟他之间也只是这样吗
Was that how it was with him?
亚伯拉罕
Abraham?
不是
No.
我爱上他了
I fell in with him
因为他看到了我能保护好自己
because he saw I could handle my shit.
我以前从不回头
And I never looked back.
不  我回头了
Well, no, I did.
在我们分手时
When it was over.
是啊
Yeah.
你知道我最受不了的是什么吗
You know the thing that killed me?
我们到亚历山大以后
When we got to Alexandria,
我表现得像完全没事一样  而他不是
I was acting like I was all good 'cause he wasn't.
然后  那个混蛋倒是真的完全没事了
Then, the son of a bitch was actually all good.
我就是想不明白
And I couldn't figure this one out.
在那里生活着  好像我们已经成功了
Living there, feeling like we had made it,
我就是适应不了
I couldn't pick that up.
然后  当他离开  我...
Then, when he bounced, I...
我以为我恨你
...I thought I hated you.
但也许我恨的只是
But maybe I just hated
他先搞明白了自己的破事
that he figured out his shit first.
我从来没和任何人说过这些
I've never told anyone any of that stuff.
我曾是谁  我做过什么
Who I was, what I did...
我很高兴
I'm glad...
你觉得你可以
that you felt like...
跟我说
you could.
我太蠢了  浪费了那么多时间
I was stupid to waste so much time.
现在我再也没有机会告诉亚伯拉罕
Now I'll never get to tell Abraham
他快乐令我也感到快乐
I'm happy he was happy.
你当时快乐吗
Were you happy?
快乐
I was.
他命不该绝
It wasn't his time.
亚伯拉罕会想在抗争中死去
Abraham would've wanted to go out fighting.
那个拿球棒的混球连这个机会都不给
And that asshole with the bat took that away, too.
死的要有意义
To go out with a point to going out.
我猜这是我们所有人都想要的
I guess we all want that.
无论最后变成什么样
No matter how it all goes down,
我是你的后盾
I got your back.
我也是你的后盾
And I've got yours.
你觉得那个混球出来了吗
You think that prick's out there yet?
该死
Oh...shit.
怎么了
What?
卡森医生  玛姬的医生
Dr. Carson, Maggie's doctor.
他们把他带来了
They brought him here.
尼根出来了
Negan's out.
他离得太近了
Oh, he's too close.
我瞄不到他
Ah, I can't get a clean shot.
打开对讲机
Turn on the walkie.
我是尤金·伯特博士  首席工程师
This is Dr. Eugene Porter, Chief Engineer, speaking.
我还需要一打行尸
I'm gonna need a dozen more walkers,
按本地说法  也就是死尸
a.k.a. "dead ones" in the local parlance,
用来扩展围栏方案  立刻去做
for expanding the fence protocol PDQ.
立刻他妈去做
Actually, PFQ.
这是尼根的要求  我也是尼根
This is per Negan, who I also am,
即便抓它们要一晚上时间
even if it takes all night to procure them,
所以我需要派体格健全的人出去
so I need able-bodied persons out there
在附近街区搜寻抓获
in the surrounding blocks of buildings
立马出发
snoopin' and snatchin', stat.
尼根会在后宫歇息  不宜见客
Negan will be indisposed in the boudoir,
所以在此期间
so in the meantime,
一切问题都直接向我汇报
any questions should be directed to yours truly.
尤金·伯特博士  首席工程师
Dr. Eugene Porter, Chief Engineer,
又名尼根  也就是我
also known as Negan, who I am.
计划改变
Change of plans.
我们进去
So we go in.
我准备好了
I'm ready.
进来
Come in.
弗莱迪说你找我
Freddie said you wanted to see me?
是的  坐吧
Yes, have a seat.
我发现你最近搜索补给和招募新人
I noticed you've been slacking on your scavenging
都很不用心
and recruiting lately.
而且你拖车里的人太多了
And there are too many people in your trailer.
火灾隐患
Fire hazard.
巴林顿公馆还有很多空房可供客人居住
Plenty of room here at Barrington House for our guests.
说到这个
Speaking of which,
我给新人们安排了工作
I have job assignments for the newcomers.
他们想留下来  就得分担工作
People are gonna stay, they're gonna chip in.
别再想搭便车了
No more free rides on the teat.
你任他们带走了卡森医生
You let them take Dr. Carson.
很惊讶你这次没下跪
Surprised you didn't kneel again.
这么急着分开大家
You must be really worried
看来你一定很担心
if you're trying to split everyone up.
你不该用那种口气跟我说话
Shouldn't talk to me like that.
谁知道救世军
Who knows what might happen
来的时候会发生什么呢
with all these Saviors coming around?
你刚是在威胁我吗
Did you just threaten me?
我只是在讽刺  好吗
I was being sarcastic, okay?
不  我觉得你刚是在威胁我
No, I think you just threatened me.
随你怎么想
Think what you want.
我只是想说
You know, what I'm saying is,
我会关照朋友
I look out for my friends,
而我意识到  我们不是朋友
and I realized... we're not friends.
进
‭Come in.
非常好  龙舌兰
Ah, wonderful -- tequila.
给我打开  好吗
Crack that open for me, would you?
你可以出去了
You may go now.
带他出去  卡尔
Show him out, will you, Kal?
没出什么事吧
Everything okay?
萨沙和罗西塔在哪
Where's Sasha and Rosita?
看到那个了吗
You see that over there?
那是个半瓶子晃荡的安全措施
That is a half-assed attempt at a safety protocol.
我们要周密  全面的防守
We need a full-assed, full-court press.
前面的那些尖矛  铁链  头颅
That stuff out front with the spikes and the chains and the heads,
视觉效果很好
that's good for the optics.
给潜在的入侵者释放了
It sends a message to would-be intruders
"别惹老子"的信息
of the "Don't Mess with Texas" Variety.
但我们要深入探讨一下真正的安全措施
But we need to drill down on actual safety protocol,
尤其是那些已被证明的薄弱点
especially at points that have proven to be janky.
好
Well, yeah.
所以才换我来值守
That's why I'm on guard duty now.
无意冒犯前一个人
No offense to that last guy,
但他连枪都拿不稳
but he could hardly handle a gun.
起来  你要出去了
Get up. You're getting out.
尤金  起来
Eugene, get up.
我们救你出去
We're breaking you out.
尤金
Eugene!
不
No.
我不跟你们走
I'm not going with you.
什么
What?
我没让你们来  所以走吧
I didn't ask you to come, so go.
肯定有人来了
People got to be en route.
懦弱  骗人的混蛋
That weak, lying sack of shit.
就现在
This is it.
我进了
I'm going in.
等等
Hold on.
这得花点时间
This is gonna take a second.
可能有更多人来
More could be coming back.
注意周围
Keep an eye out.
马上就好
Just another second.
你在做什么
What the hell are you doing?
走吧
Go.
你命不该绝
It's not your time.
必须有所意义  对吗
There's got to be a point to it, right?
他们需要你
They need you.
该死
Damn it.
Damn it!